He loves her. She loves him not.
Just Friends is a comedy, romance film directed by Roger Kumble.
While visiting his hometown during Christmas, a man comes face-to-face with his old high school crush whom he
was best friends with – a woman whose rejection of him turned him into a ferocious womanizer.
Chris Brander, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Jamie Palamino, played by Amy Smart.
Samantha James, played by Anna Faris.
Dusty Dinkleman, played by Chris Klein.
Mike Brander, played by Christopher Rodriguez Marquette.
Carol Brander, played by Julie Hagerty.
Just Friends is a 2005 Christmas romantic black comedy film directed by Roger Kumble, written by Adam 'Tex'
Davis and starring Ryan Reynolds, Amy Smart, Anna Faris, Chris Klein and Christopher Marquette.
The plot focuses on a formerly obese high school student (Reynolds) who attempts to free himself from the friend zone after
reconnecting with his best friend (Smart), with whom he is in love while visiting his hometown for Christmas.
The film revolves around humorous observation of strictly platonic
relationships as "just friends" or "just as best friends".
Davis's screenplay for Just Friends was initially optioned in 2001 by New Line
Cinema, and was inspired by numerous elements of his own life.
Principal photography took place in early 2005 in Los Angeles as
well as Regina and Moose Jaw, Saskatchewan, Canada.
The film was an international co-production between
the United States, Canada, and Germany.
Just Friends was released on November 23, 2005, and grossed over $50 million.
It received mixed reviews from film critics, but has developed a
cult following in the years since its release.
The film explores themes of change, holiday, success, falling in love, hometown.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.